我有字幕啦 百姓网啊啊啊
You've seen me draw a few pictures of your neural network in this video
我们将讨论 这些图形的具体含义
we'll talk about exactly what those pictures means
换句话说 就是我们画的这些神经网络
in other words exactly what those little neural networks
到底代表什么
have been drawing on represent
我们先集中精力看看
and we'll starts with focusing on the case of
只有一个隐藏层的神经网络
neural networks with what's called a single hidden layer
这是一张神经网络图
here's a picture of a neural network
我们命名一下这张图的各部分
let's give different parts of these pictures some names
我们有输入特征x1 x2 x3 竖向堆叠起来
we have the input features x1 x2 x3 stacked vertically
这是神经网络的输入层
and this is called the input layer of the neural network
没什么特别的
so maybe not surprisingly
它包含了神经网络的输入
this contains the inputs to the neural network
然后这里有另外一层的圆圈
then there's another layer of circles
我们称之为神经网络的隐藏层
and this is called a hidden layer of the neural network
我们马上会讲到 "隐藏"是什么意思
I'll come back in a second to say what the word hidden means
这里的最后一层
but the final layer here is formed
在这里只有一个节点
by in this case just one node
而这个只带一个节点的层就是输出层
and this single note layer is called the output layer
它负责输出 预测值y帽
and it's responsible for generating the predicted value y hat.
在一个神经网络中 当你使用监督学习训练它的时候
In a neural network the you train with supervised learning
训练集包含了输入x
the training set contains values of the inputs x
还有目标输出y
as well as the target outputs y
“隐藏层”的含义是
so the term hidden layer refers to the fact that
在训练集中 这些中间节点的真正数值
in a training set the true values for these nodes
我们是不知道的
in the middle are not observed
在训练集你看不到它们的数值
that is you don't see what they should be in the training set
你能看到输入值
you see what the inputs are
也能看见输出值
you see what the output should be
但是隐藏层中的值
but the things in a hidden layer
在训练集中 是无法看到的
are not seen in the training set
这就是所谓的“隐藏层”
so that kind of explains the name hidden layer
只是表示你无法在训练集中看到
just means you don't see it in a training set
现在我们再引入几个符号
let's introduce a bit more notation
之前我们用向量x表示输入特征
whereas previously we were using the vector x to denote the input features
输入特征的数值还有另外一种表示方式
an alternative notation for the values of the input features
我们用a^[0]来表示
will be a superscript square bracket 0
而这个a 也表示"激活"的意思
and the term a also stands for activations
它意味着网络中不同层的值
and it refers to the values that different layers of the neural network
会传递给后面的层
are passing on to the subsequent layers
输入层将x的值 传递给隐藏层
so the input layer passes on the value x to the hidden layer
我们将输入层的激活值
so we're going to call that
称为a上标[0]
call the activations of the input layer a superscript 0
下一层即隐藏层
the next layer the hidden layer
也同样会产生一些激活值
will in turn generate some set of activations
那么我将其记作 a^[1]
which I'm going to write as a superscript square bracket 1
具体地 这里的第一个单元 或者说节点
so in particular this first unit or this first node
我们将其表示为 a^[1]_1
we generate the value a superscript square bracket 1 subscript 1
第二个节点 我们记为 a^[1]2 以此类推
this second node we generate the value now with a subscript 2 and so on
这里的a^[1]
and so a superscript square bracket 1
是一个四维向量
this is a four dimensional vector
写成Python代码
or if you write it in Python
它是一个4x1矩阵 或大小为4的列向量
it gives us a four by one matrix or four column vector
就像我画的这样 它是四维的
which looks like this and it's four dimensional
是因为在本例中 我们有四个节点
because in this case we have four nodes
有四个单元 四个隐藏层单元
or four units or four hidden units in this hidden layer
最后的输出层
then finally the output layer
会产生某个数值a^[2] 是个实数
will generate some value a^[2] which is just a real number
y帽的值就等于a^[2]
and so y hat is going to take on the value of a^[2]
所以这和 logistic回归类似
so this is analogous to how in logistic regression
在logistic回归中 y帽等于a
we have y hat equals a and in logistic regression
我们只有一个输出层
we only had that one output layer
所以没有用带方括号的上标
so we didn't use the superscript square bracket
但是在神经网络中
but with a neural network
我们将使用这种方括号上标
we're now going to use this superscript square bracket
来明确地指出这些值来自哪一层
to explicitly indicate which layer it came from
有趣的是 在约定俗成的符号中
one funny thing about notational conventions in neural networks
在这里你看到的这个例子
is that this network that you're seeing here
是所谓的双层神经网络
is called a two layer neural network
当我们计算网络的层数时
and the reason is that when we count layers in neural networks
不算入输入层的原因是
we don't count the input layer
隐藏层是第一层
so the hidden layer is layer 1
输出层是第二层
and the output layer is layer two
在我们的符号约定中
In our notational convention
我们将输入层称为第零层
we're calling the input layer layer 0
所以在字面上可以说
so technically maybe there are
这是一个“三层的”神经网络
three layers in this neural network
因为这里有输入层 隐藏层
because this is input layer the hidden layer
还有输出层  但一般符号的约定是
and the output layer but in conventional users
如果你阅读研究论文 或者在这门课中
if you read research papers and also in the course
你会看到人们将这个神经网络
you see people refer to this particular neural network
称为双层神经网络
as a two layer neural network
因为我们不把输入层 看作一个标准的层
because we don't count input layer as a as an official layer
最后我们要知道
finally something that we'll get to later
隐藏层 以及最后的输出层
is that the hidden layer and the output layers
是带有参数的
will have parameters associated with it
这里的隐藏层有两个相关的参数W和b
so the hidden layer will have associated with their parameters w and b
使用上标[1]
and I'm going to write superscript square bracket 1
表示这些参数
to indicate that these are parameters
是和第一层这个隐藏层有关的
associated with layer 1 with a hidden layer
之后我们会看到 W是一个4x3的矩阵
we'll see later that W will be a 4 by 3 matrix
而b在这个例子中是一个4x1向量
and b will be a 4 by 1 vector in this example
第一个数字4
where the first coordinate 4
意思是有四个节点 或者说四个隐藏单元
comes from the fact that we have four nodes or four hidden units
然后数字3来自
there and three comes from the fact
这里有三个输入特征
that we have three input features
之后会更加详细地 讨论这些矩阵的维数
we'll talk later about the dimensions of these matrices
到那时 你可能就更明白了
and it might make more sense at that time
类似地 输出层也有一些
but in similarly the output layer has associated with it
和它有关的参数W^[2]
also parameters w superscript square bracket 2
以及b^[2]
and b superscript square bracket 2
从维数来看
and it turns out that the dimensions of these
分别是1x4以及1x1
are one by four and one by one
这是1×4 是因为隐藏层有四个隐藏单元
and this one by fours because the hidden layer has four hidden units
而输出层只有一个单元
the output layer has just one unit
之后的视频中 我们会对这些矩阵和向量的维度
and we're going we'll go over the dimensions
做更加深入的解释
of these matrices and vectors in a later video
所以你现在已经知道 一个双层神经网络是怎样的
so you've just seen what a two layer neural network looks like
它是只有一个隐藏层的神经网络
that is a neural network with one hidden layer
在下一个视频中 我们将更深入地
in the next video let's go deeper into exactly
了解这个神经网络到底在计算什么
what this neural network is computing
这个神经网络是怎么输入x
that is how this neural network inputs x
然后又是怎么一直算下去得到y帽的
and goes all the way to computing this output y hat